Finding Aid for the Allen Sapp Score Collection, circa 1936-1992
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Allen Sapp Score Collection, circa 1936-1992
Mus. Arc. 11.1
Sapp, Allen, 1922-1999
31 boxes (343 folders)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library 112 Baird Hall Buffalo, New York 14260-4750 United States Phone: 716 645-2924 Fax: 716 645-3906
The Allen Sapp Score Collection contains manuscript and holograph scores of works composed by Allen Sapp. The collection also contains some of Sapp's drafts, outlines, and twelve-tone row forms and matrices; as well as exercises, analysis, and arrangements of other composer's works completed while at Harvard University.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
The collection was given to the Music Library by Allen Sapp's sons, Christopher S. Dawson and Anthony C. Sapp.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Allen Sapp was born in Philadelphia on December 10, 1922. He began piano lessons at an early age, developed an interest in music composition, and began performing his own work at the age of ten. After graduating from the Haverford School in 1939, he entered Harvard University, where he studied with Walter Piston, Archibald T. Davison, and Irving Fine. Many of Sapp's works were performed while he was an undergraduate, including the Andante for Orchestra, which won second prize in the New York Philharmonic Young Composer's Contest, and was performed by that group in April 1942.
Also in 1942, Sapp graduated from Harvard and was awarded the John Knowles Paine Fellowship, which allowed him to attend Tanglewood and to begin private composition lessons with Aaron Copland and Nadia Boulanger. After serving as a cryptanalyst in the U.S. Army during W.W.II, Sapp returned to Harvard and earned a Master's degree in 1949. He then joined the faculty at Harvard, teaching there until 1958, and at Wellesley College from 1958-61.
From 1961 to 1975 Sapp was chair of the Music Department of the University at Buffalo, The State University of New York. During this time, he helped establish the university as a leading center for experimental and new music, co-founding the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts with Lukas Foss in 1964. Sapp also assumed leadership positions in several national arts organizations, including Arts/Worth and the American Council for the Arts in Education, of which he was elected executive director in 1972.
Sapp later served as Provost for Communications and the Arts at Florida State University from 1976-78; and as Dean, then Professor of Composition, at the University of Cincinnati College-Conservatory of Music from 1978-93. In 1986 he was awarded the George Rieveschl Award for Distinguished Creative and Scholarly Works at the University of Cincinnati, and in 1993 was commissioned by the Cincinnati Chamber Orchestra to write a commemorative work for the group's twentieth anniversary. His works have also been performed by the Philharmonia Orchestra of the University of Cincinnati College-Conservatory of Music, the Cincinnati Wind Ensemble, the Buffalo Philharmonic, the Ohio University Chamber Orchestra, l'Orchestre de la Radiodiffusion Française, and the Boston Fine Arts Chamber orchestra.
Scope and Content Note
The Allen Sapp Score Collection, ca. 1936-1992, contains 343 folders of paper, vellum, or Multilith manuscript scores; bound and unbound performance parts; ozalid or photocopied reproductions of scores and parts; manuscript notebooks; and outlines on graph, staff, or lined writing paper. Overall, approximately 180 complete works are represented.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in seven series:
I. Manuscripts of Works Assigned a "W" Number in Allen Sapp: A Bio-Bibliography, by Alan Green (Greenwood Press, 1996)
II. Manuscripts of Titled Works Not Assigned a "W" Number
III. Manuscripts of Works Without Titles or Numbers
IV. Sketches and Fragmentary Works
V. Row Forms, Matrices, and Outlines
VI. Manuscript Books and Exercises
VII. Arrangements, Transcriptions, and Analyses of Other Composer's Works
Container List
- Manuscripts of Works Assigned a "W" Number in Allen Sapp: A Bio-Bibliography, by Alan Green (Greenwood Press, 1996), 1939-1994, I.; Box 1-26 (211 folders)
  Titles are stated as they appear in the above bibliography, organized by the work numbers assigned in that book. Alternative titles taken directly from the manuscripts, when present, are listed as a second, un-italicized title. Dates are taken directly from manuscripts. In cases where conflicting dates are indicated, both are included, along with their location on the manuscript. Unless otherwise noted, manuscripts are paper.
  Arranged in ascending order by "W" number.
  - W1 Piano Sonata I Sonata for Piano March 13, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    For keyboard solo
    I. Andante II. Allegro
    Ink holograph, annotated (corrected staves attached to original, pg 7), 13 p.
  - W2 January Eighth 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Ink holograph, 2 p.
    Inscription on 2nd page, signed P. Lion.
  - W3 Two Short Moods for Piano Jan. 11, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    I. Lassitude II. Mighty Lak a Piece named Toccata by a Certain M. Ravel
    Ink holograph, 4 p.
  - W4 Four Scenes in One Act Jan. 19, 1943 (I); Jan. 21, 1943 (II); Jan. 23, 1943 (III); Jan. 22, 1943 (IV). (Box 1, Folder 4)
    I. Gray Day II. Washington: Union Station III. Praeludium IV. End
    Ink holograph, 10 p.
  - W5 Two Etudes Feb. 10, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    I. Etude -- II. Etude II
  - W6 21 April 7, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - W7 Pigeons May 19, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Ink holograph, 4 p. With: Chicken; ink holograph, 1+ p., unfinished
  - W8 Prelude and Finale Prelude Aug. 11, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Ink holograph, annotated, 4 p.
    Prelude crossed out in caption, Finale written in pencil.
  - W8 Prelude and Finale Finale Aug. 13, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Ink holograph, annotated, 2 p.
    No title page. Finale crossed out above 1st page of music, Intermezzo written in pencil.
  - W9 Anniversary Anniversary I May 31, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Ink holograph, vellum, 1 p.
  - W10 Pearl May 31, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - W11 Novelette Feb. 21, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Ink holograph, 3 p.
  - W12 Piano Sonatina I Sonatina for Piano July 1945 (title page), Sept. 1, 1945 (last page) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Ink holograph, vellum, 10 leaves
  - W14 Suite for Piano Suite for Piano (Eb) 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    I. Allegro II. Adagio III. Allegretto IV. Andante V. Allegro Molto
    Pencil holograph, 11 leaves, annotated
  - W15 Seven Bagatelles for Piano Oct. 1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Ink holograph, vellum, 12 leaves
  - W15 Seven Bagatelles for Piano Oct. 10, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Pencil and paper holograph of 1st bagatelle, 1 p.
    Inscription: Autograph " Bagatelle Allen Sapp, in pen.
  - W16 Piano Sonata II II Piano Sonata 1957 (title pg.); 1954-56 (1st pg.); June 1, 1957 (last page, also inscribed Revised Edition) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    I. Larghetto II. Allegro Molto III. Andantino IV. Allegro
    Ink holograph, vellum, 19 leaves
  - W16 Piano Sonata II II Piano Sonata 1957 (title pg.); 1954-56 (1st pg.); June 1, 1957 (last page, also inscribed Revised Edition) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Reproduction of vellum holograph, last movement only, annotated 6 p.
    Pages are taped side-by-side, with extra paper backing, to be folded out for performance.
  - W17 Four Impromptus for Piano Feb. 23, 1957 (end of 1st impromptu); Feb. 18, 1957 (end of 2nd impromptu) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 8 leaves.
    Copied June 8, 1957 written in ink on title page. Includes two copies of 1st impromptu.
  - W17 Four Impromptus for Piano Feb. 23, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Ink holograph, vellum, 7 leaves
  - W19 Piano Sonata III III Piano Sonata March 15, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    I. Allegro Molto II. Adagio III. Agitato
    Ink holograph, vellum, 20 leaves
  - W19 Piano Sonata III Feb. 15, 1957 (I); March 15, 1957 (III) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Pencil manuscript, annotated, 16 leaves.
  - W20 Piano Sonata IV IV Piano Sonata August 12, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    I. Decisively II. Slowly III. Fluently
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 15 leaves
  - W20 Piano Sonata IV IV Piano Sonata August 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Ink holograph, vellum, 21 leaves
  - W21 Fantasy I: "The Pursuers" Fantasy undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Pencil, annotated, 5 leaves
  - W21 Fantasy I: "The Pursuers" Fantasy for Piano "The Pursuers" July 6, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Ink holograph, vellum, annotated (pedal markings and performance instructions, in ink and pencil), 10 leaves
  - W22 Untitled [four preludes for piano] undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Ink, 5 p.
  - W23 Piano Sonata V Piano Sonata V in One Movement August 26, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 21 p.
  - W23 Piano Sonata V undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    3 pages of material relating to W23: Text Description of musical characteristics; Row forms (10 total); Row forms (48 total)
  - W24 Piano Sonata VI Sept. 28, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    I. Gracefully II. Brilliante
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 20 leaves
  - W24 Piano Sonata VI Sixth Sonata for Piano 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    I. Gracefully II. Brilliantly
    Pencil holograph, 28 p.
  - W24 Piano Sonata VI Pf. Sonata VI undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Pencil manuscript, 2 leaves.
    Leaves marked "5" and "6"
  - W24 Piano Sonata VI undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    2 p. of material relating to W24: Text, Description, dated December 15; Row forms
  - W25 Piano Sonata VII: "Conversations with Friends" Sonata VII (Conversations with Friends) December 18, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    I. Introspectively II. Violently III. Playfully IV. Seriously V. Brightly
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 36 p.
  - W25 Piano Sonata VII: "Conversations with Friends" December 18, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Photocopy of no. 9 above, annotated (movement order on title page altered).
    Includes 1 p. of program and biographical notes.
  - W26 Five Toccatas for Solo Harpsichord July 1, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    I. Lively II. Tempo Rubato III. Quarter note = 84 IV. Brilliantly V. Eighth note=80
    Pencil holograph, 13 p.
  - W29 Five Inventions for Piano 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    I. Rapidly II. Expressively III. Smoothly IV. Andante V. Crisply
    Pencil manuscript, 5 leaves
  - W30 Up in the Sky 1984-85 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    I. Companion Stars II. Waltz of the Dwarf Stars III. Galactic Storm IV. March of the Planets V. Cassiopeia VI. Mercury on a Trip VII. A Giant Red Star VIII. Interstellar Dust IX. Cosmic Particles in a Rush X. The Big Bear Constellation XI. Cold Space Beyond Pluto XII. Harmony of the Spheres XIII. Comet with a Long Tail XIV. Moonshine XV. Andromeda XVI. Black Holes XVII. Galaxy's End XVIII. After the Nova XIX. Saturn's Rings XX. Meteorite XXI. Arcturus
    Pencil and ink holograph, annotated, 21 leaves
  - W31 Piano Sonata VIII 1983-1985 (title pg.), July 10, 1985 (colophon) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    I. Moderately II. Sixteenth note=80, Iridescently III. Vehemently
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 37 leaves
  - W31 Piano Sonata VIII 1983-1985 (title pg.), July 10, 1985/ July 4, 1986 (colophon) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Ink holograph, 53 p.
  - W32 Epithalamium Epithalamium for Organ January- April 1986 (title p.), April 20, 1986 (colophon) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 28 leaves.
    Performance instructions given on pg. 1.
  - W34 Piano Sonata IX April 12, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    I. Fast and Ferocious! (After a sermon of Donne) II. Presto (Scherzo) III. Intimately (Nocturne) IV. Agreeably but Rapidly! Rondeletto)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 16 leaves
  - W35 Piano Sonata X Spring 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 14 leaves
  - W38 Farewell June 1, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - NA Synapses December 1993-Jan. 1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Ink holograph, 2 leaves
  - NA Punkin's song [195-?] (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Ink holograph, 1 leaf
  - W41 Fantasy III: Homage to Mendelssohn Sept. 21, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Ink holograph, annotated, 16 p.
  - W43 Four Dialogues for Two Pianos December 4-6, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    For piano duet
    Pencil holograph, draft.
    Two copies of Dialogues I and II; extra title page marked "Second Copy" with "Three" crossed out in title and "Four" written above. Also, 1 p. manuscript of pencil sketches, marked "Trio I," included with other material.
  - W43 Four Dialogues for Two Pianos 1954-55 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    I. Adagietto II. Con Anima III. Commodo IV. Vivace
    Ink holograph, vellum, 17 leaves.
  - W44 Four Hand Piano Sonata II Second Four Hand Sonata for Piano 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    I. Allegro Semplice (alla francese) II. Andante III. Allegro Assai
    Pencil holograph, 26 p.
  - W45 Four Hand Piano Sonata III Third Four Hand Sonata 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Pencil and ink manuscript (no signature), draft, annotated
  - W45 Four Hand Piano Sonata III Third Four Hand Sonata for Piano 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Chorales I " Scherzo " Chorales II
  - W 45 Four Hand Piano Sonata III Four Hand Pfte Sonata III | Variation VI (mm. 111-140) | in improved score undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Ink manuscript, 4 p.
  - W46 Aquarelles 1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    I. Beams II. A Poor Young Shepherd III. Streets IV. Green V. Child Wife VI. Spleen
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 29 leaves
  - W47 Eaux- Fortes December 1983- January 1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    I. Croquis de Paris II. Cauchemar III. Marine IV. Effet de Nuit V. Grotesques
    Pen and pencil holograph, annotated, 40 leaves.
    Ink copies (translations") of "Eaux- Fortes" included.
  - W47 Eaux- Fortes December 1983-January 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Ink holograph, 41 p.
  - W48 Suite for Two Flutes and Piano 1940 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    I. Prelude II. Sarabande III. Gigue IV. Pavane
    Ink holograph, annotated, 28 p.
    Includes copies of flute parts, incomplete.
  - W49 Four Movements for Three Stringed Instruments 1941 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    For violin, viola, violoncello
    I. Allegro II. Lento III. Allegretto IV. Allegro Molto
    Ink holograph, 27 p.
  - W50 Sonata Movement for String Trio undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Ink holograph, 20 p.
  - W51 Cello Sonata First Theme of Cello Sonata undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    For cello and piano
    Pencil and ink manuscript, draft
  - W52 Violin Sonata I undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    For violin and piano
    Ink holograph, annotated, 17 p.
  - W52 Violin Sonata I Two- Thirds of a Sonata for Violin and Piano 1942 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Ink title page, no music included. Complete transcription: To Viviane Bertolami | Two- Thirds of a | Sonata for Violin | and Piano | Allen Sapp | 1942
  - W53 And the Bombers Went Home Jan. 15, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - W53 And the Bombers Went Home April 1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - W54 Violin Sonata II Second Violin Sonata 1948 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Pencil and ink holograph, draft, 27 p
  - W54 Violin Sonata II Second Violin Sonata undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Pencil and ink sketches, 13 p.
  - W54 Violin Sonata II 1948 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    I. Allegro ma non troppo II. Larghetto III. Presto
    Ink holograph, annotated, 40 p.
  - W55 Viola Sonata undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    For viola and piano
    Pencil manuscript, draft, 22 p.
  - W56 Piano Trio Trio undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    For piano, violin, cello
    I. Lento II. Agitato III. Commodo IV. Allegro Molto
    Pencil manuscript, draft, 19 p.
  - W56 Piano Trio 1949 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Ink holograph, annotated, 15 p.
    Violin and cello parts only.
  - W57 String Quartet I String Quartet in E 1951 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    I. Allegro II. Andantino III. Adagio
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 29 p.
  - W57 String Quartet I String Quartet in E undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Pencil manuscript, sketches, 15 p.
  - W57 String Quartet I String Quartet in E 1951 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    parts, reproductions: 11 first violin; 9 second violin; 13 viola; 14 cello
  - W58 Chaconne for Violin and Organ Chaconne undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    For violin and organ
    Pencil manuscript, annotated, 4 leaves
  - W59 Six Ricercare for Viols Oct. 1956 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    For viol ensemble
    I. Slowly II. Vigorously III. Vigorously IV. Quite Slowly V. Moderate VI. Vigorously
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 8 leaves
  - W59 Six Ricercare for Viols Oct. 1956 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Ink holograph, vellum, 9 leaves
  - W60 String Trio Trio for Violin, Viola, Violoncello 1956 (title pg.); Feb. 1957 (colophon) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    I. Allegro Grazioso II. Andante III. Vivace
    Ink holograph, vellum, 28 leaves
  - W60 String Trio Trio 1956 (title pg.); Feb 1957 (colophon) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Ink holograph, vellum.
    Parts only.
  - W60 String Trio Trio for Violin, Viola, and Violoncello 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 24 leaves
  - W61 Six Variations on the Hymn-Tune "Durant" Variations on Durant April 17, 1960 (title pg.); "finished Feb. 14, 1960" (colophon) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    For flute, oboe, English horn, bassoon
    Theme, Var. I (HH), Var. II (HWL), Var III (WAH), Var IV (ADS), Var. V (HB), Var. VI (CA)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 11 leaves
  - W61 6 Variations on the Hymn-Tune "Durant" 1960 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - W62 Violin Sonata III 1960 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    I. Adagietto II. Presto III. Allegro Energico
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 23 leaves.
    Five leaves of pencil sketches included.
  - W62 Violin Sonata III Sonata III for Violin and Piano Nov. 1960 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    I. Allegro Energico II. Adagietto III. Presto
  - W63 Variations on A Solis Ortus Cardine December 1962 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    For 2 violins, viola, cello, double bass, oboe, horn
    I. Cantus in Bass II. Canon at Unison III. Canon at 7th IV. Cantus in all Parts V. Canon at 5th VI. Canon at 6th VII. Cantus in Alto VIII. Cantus in Bass
    Pencil and ink holograph, annotated, 25 leaves.
    Re-written sections from other pages stapled to holograph. Program from 1962 performance at UB included.
  - W63 Variations on A Solis Ortus Cardine December 1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Ink manuscript parts
  - W64 Irregular Polygon Nov. 12, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    For 2 violins, viola, cello
    Ink holograph, 1 p.
  - W66 String Quartet II Quartet II undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Ink manuscript parts only.
    Photocopies included.
  - W66 String Quartet II undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    I. Moderately II. Allegro Molto III. Moderately
    Pencil holograph, draft, 36 p.
  - W66 String Quartet II 1981 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    I. Moderately II. Very Fast III. Moderately
    Pencil holograph, 45 p.
  - W67 Taylor"s Nine 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    For 2 marimbas, bells, xylophone, glockenspiel, vibraphone, celesta or electric piano
    Pencil holograph, 32 p.
  - W68 Violin Sonata IV Sonata IV for Violin and Piano 1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    I. Roughly II. Slowly
    Ink holograph, 36 p.
    9 p. ink holograph violin part included.
  - W69 String Quartet III 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    I. Grazioso II. Moderately III. Vivace IV. Agitato
    Pencil holograph, draft, 19 leaves.
    Movements I-III notated as piano score; Movement IV scored for string quartet.
  - W69 String Quartet III March 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    I. Grazioso II. Adagietto III. Vivace IV. Agitato
  - W70 String Quartet IV March 1981 (colophon) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 16 p.
  - W70 String Quartet IV March 1981 (colophon) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Slowly- Violently- Moderately- Violently-Slowly
    Pencil holograph, 19 p.
  - W71 Colloquies II Oct. 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    For flute, viola
    Ink holograph, 8 leaves
  - W71 Colloquies II "1978 (82)" (Box 6, Folder 6)
    For piano, flute, viola
    Ink holograph, 11 leaves
  - W72 Five Pieces for Solo Violin in the Language of Flowers May 1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    For violin
    I. Moderately II. Quickly III. Azalea IV. Bougainvillea V. Rhododendron
    photocopy of ink holograph, 5 leaves
  - W73 Sirius :: Stella Canis | The Companion of Sirius :: The Serious Companion Jan. " Feb. 1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    For tuba and piano
    I. Sirius :: Stella Canis II. The Companion of Sirius :: The Serious Companion
    Ink holograph, 10 leaves.
  - W74 Colloquies IV: "The Lament for Adonis" Colloquies IV undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    For full orchestra
    notes and sketches for orchestral version of this work
  - W78 Fantasia: "Shiny Dumplings Rising Like Bubbles of Air, Clockwise" Fantasia: "Shiny Dumplings Rising Like Bubbles of Air, Clockwise" (Sigrid Ottersten) March 1986 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Pencil holograph, 18 leaves (score); ink holograph, 5 leaves (violin part).
    Photocopy of violin part included.
  - W79 Colloquies V: "The Cage of All Bright Knocks" Colloquy V: The Cage of All Bright Knocks undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    For alto flute and piano
    Pencil manuscript, draft, 11 leaves
  - W79 "Colloquy V: "The Cage of All Bright Knocks" Oct. 10, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Ink holograph, 13 p.
  - W81 Colloquies VI: "Socrates and Phaedrus Speak of Love on the Banks of the Illisus" June-October 1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    For oboe and piano
    Ink holograph, annotated, 10 p.
  - W82 Inscriptions and Commentaries Spring- August 8, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    For oboe, violin, viola, cello
    Pencil holograph, 17 leaves
  - W83 Polyhedra July- November 24, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    For woodwind quintet: flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon, French horn
    I. Tetrahedron II. Cube III. Octahedron IV. Icosahedron V. Dodecahedron
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 17 leaves.
    Program notes bound with score.
  - W83 Polyhedra July- November 24, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    photocopies of manuscript parts
  - W84 Bridal Song 1951-52 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    For mezzo-soprano, flute, violin, viola, cello
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 10 leaves
  - W85 Nursery Rhymes "Ride a Cock-Horse," "Old Mother Hubbard," "Little Jack Horner," "Hickory Dickory Dock" undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    For voice and piano
    Pencil manuscript, annotated, 5 leaves
  - W86 7 Epigrams (Both Sweet and Sour) 1952 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    For bass voice and piano
    I. Grazioso II. Andante III. Feroce IV. Pesante V. Marzile VI. Andante VII. Animato
    Pencil holograph, draft, 7 leaves
  - W86 7 Epigrams (Both Sweet and Sour) 1952 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Ink holograph, vellum, 10 leaves.
    24 paper copies included.
  - W87 Lady and the Lute Eight Songs for Soprano and Harpsichord (to Texts of Robert Herrick) 1952 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    I. Andante II. Allegretto III. Adagio IV. Graziero V. Andante VI. Allegro VII. Feroce VIII. Waltz Time
    Pencil holograph, draft, 17 leaves
  - W87 Lady and the Lute The Lady and the Lute: A Song Cycle for Soprano and Piano 1952 (title page), "This edition, Rome, 1957" (colophon) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    I. Con Tenerezza II. Giocoso III. Troppo Serioso IV. Con Passione V. Voluttuosamente VI. Astutamente VII. Feroce VIII. Con Tenerezza
    Ink holograph, vellum, 18 leaves. 1 paper copy included.
  - W88 "Two Lyrics for Voice and Piano" Nov. 30, 1961 (I); Nov. 14, 1961 (II) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    For high voice and piano
    I. Slowly II. Quickly
    Pencil holograph, 2 p.
  - W88 Seven Songs of Carew Two Lyrics for Voice and Piano Nov. 30, 1961 (I); Nov. 14, 1961 (II) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    For voice (not specified) and piano
    Ink holograph, vellum, 4 p. Notes: paper copy included
  - W88 Seven Songs of Carew 1961 (I- II); 1982 (III- VII) (Box 7, Folder 7)